Mandar Shinde

Senior Technical Writer | Certified SAFe® 5 Scrum Master | Certified SAFe® 5 Product Owner/Product Manager

More than ten years of experience delivering technical publications for emerging technologies and products. Demonstrated track record of handling end-to-end documentation of products and projects.

manvshinde@gmail.com

+91 8446597048

Pune, India



WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Information Developer

Druva

06/2022 - Present Pune

Senior Technical Specialist

Brillio

11/2020 - 06/2022 Pune

Content Architect

EdgeVerve Systems Limited

05/2019 - 11/2020 Pune

Lead Writer

HCL Technologies Ltd.

06/2017 - 05/2019 Pune

Technical Writer II

Redknee Solutions Inc.

09/2015 - 06/2017 Pune

Technical Communications Specialist

Schlumberger

11/2014 - 08/2015 Pune

Technical Writer

3DPLM Software Solutions Limited

04/2013 - 11/2014 Pune

Technical Writer

Siemens PLM Software India Private Limited

10/2012 - 03/2013 Pune

EDUCATION

Post Graduate Diploma in ManagementAll India Council of Technical Education

2011

Courses

Finance

Bachelor of Computer Science

Pune University

2008

Courses

Computer Science

HIGHLIGHTS

Collaborated with stakeholder groups across the organization to ensure the alignment concerning deliverables. Proposed solutions for process blockers and needs.

Completed in-depth analysis by creating separate documentation tickets and dashboards for each release. Measurable outcomes improved delivery features in documents on time before the release deadline.

Performed quality assurance, system integration, and user acceptance testing for new or modified features as per the use cases in the documentation deliverables.

Creating documentation input and documentation review tickets for tracking the end-to-end documentation process.

Extensive experience in understanding and translating requirements into Webhelp, User Guides, Installation Guides, and Release Notes in SaaS, CAD/CAE domain, oil and natural gas industry, and telecom industry.

Understanding of content management systems such as Microsoft Team Foundation Server (TFS), Perforce, Concurrent Version System (CVS), Sharepoint Server 2016, Atlassian Confluence, SDL Knowledge Center, MindTouch, and GitLab.

Expert Level user of tools: MindTouch Editor, XMetaL Author Enterprise XML Editor, Arbortext Editor, Oxygen XML Author 21, Atom Editor, Adobe Structured and Unstructured Framemaker, Adobe Robohelp, MadCap Flare V10, Draw.io, and Atlassian Confluence.

A DAY OF MY LIFE

Interviewing stakeholders to gather requirements about new features developed or existing features to be improved.

Creating JIRA tickets for requirements by asking questions like who, what, when, where, and why.

Creating and maintaining documentation plan for the upcoming releases.

Attending feature demo meetings with the systems verification team, development team, and product owners for understanding the documentation impact.